Guide to the Todd-Bingham Picture Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
This section contains those glass negatives too large to be stored in conventional negative boxes (52-92) These boxes (159-67; Glass negative folios 1-2) contain those negatives 6 1/2" x 8 1/2," 8" x 10," 10" x 12," and 12" x 15". Cross references in the Glass negatives section provide access to these items.
Prints
This section contains the positive photographic prints from Glass negatives and Lantern slides, arranged as these sections are arranged. The numbered prints available are listed under the appropriate headings used in Glass negatives and Lantern slides.
Film negatives
This section contains 35mm film negatives for those lantern slides which have been reproduced as positive prints. To constantly reproduce photographs from lantern slides is both expensive and time-consuming, thus film negatives have been created for selected slides.
SERIES IV, SMALL FOLIOS, consists of twelve folios which hold those photographs, prints, drawings, and memorabilia too large for standard storage boxes. Boxes 173 and 174 contain several views of Amherst College buildings as well as scenes of "The Convent," a private girls' school run by Mary E. Stearns. Boxes 175 and 176 consist of views of the Bobinsky estate in Russia, site of the aborted 1914 eclipse observations and the observatory in Capetown, South Africa. Box 177 includes a group of color prints by a professional photographer-artist from Japan. In addition to these artistic depictions of Japanese women and daily life, there are several photographs of the Ainu people of Japan, ca. 1896. Box 178 also contains woodblock prints, drawings, and artwork of Japanese subjects. Boxes 179 to 184 contain photographic portraits and sketches of David Peck Todd, Mabel Loomis Todd, Eben Jenks Loomis, and several family friends. There are also color prints from Bermuda (1905), the Columbian Exposition (1893), and Europe (ca1910). Please note that boxes 173-184 were originally numbered Folio 1 through 12.
SERIES V, LARGE FOLIOS, contains those items generally larger than the twelve by fifteen inch size limit for SERIES IV, SMALL FOLIOS. Box 185 contains portraits, class photographs, maps, certificates, and posters of Millicent Todd Bingham. Included here are materials from her Vassar College years and certificates from two geographic societies.
Box 186 contains similar material for David Peck Todd, including astronomical drawings and charts as well as certificates, diplomas, and portraits.
Box 187 contains items pertaining to Mabel Loomis Todd. Among these materials are her sketches, certificates from the Daughters of the American Revolution, and posters announcing her lectures.
Boxes 188 and 189 contain miscellaneous material. Prints from Japan as well as surveys of family property in Fairhaven, Massachusetts are arranged here.
Please note that boxes 185 to 189 were originally numbered folios 1-5.
SERIES VI, DAGUERREOTYPES, contains over forty daguerreotypes, tintypes, and ambrotypes of Loomis, Wilder, and Todd family members. Two daguerreotypes of William Austin Dickinson, one of Susan Gilbert Dickinson, and several unidentified items are also arranged here.
Among the portraits included in this series are: Collette, Eben Jenks, George, Mary Sears, Nathan, Sarah Elizabeth Denham, and Waite Jenks Barber Loomis. John (Reverend), Mary Alden, and Mary Wales Fobes Jones Wilder. One ambrotype is identified as "M. W. Warner." Many items are undated but span dates for those items which are dated are 1855-1870.
SERIES VII, PAINTINGS, are in 6 boxes. One painting, "Mabel Loomis Todd at Matsuba," is signed by Howard Hilder, a close family friend.
Biographical / Historical
The Todd-Bingham family includes Mabel Loomis Todd (1856-1932), David Peck Todd (1855-1939), and Millicent Todd Bingham (1880-1968). Individual biographical sketches for these people are available in records for manuscript collections MS 496B, MS 496C, and MS 496D, respectively. Members of the Loomis-Wilder family are also related to the Todd-Bingham family, and a biographical sketch of Loomis-Wilder family members is available in the record for manuscript collection MS 496A.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Due to the physical nature of the materials in series III and VI, staff supervision is required.
Astronomy -- Observations; Balloons in astronomy; Solar eclipses; Mars (Planet); Africa; Ainu (Japan); Amherst (Mass.); Chile; Esashi-shi (Japan); Hawaii; Japan; Massachusetts; Peru; Shirakawa-shi (Japan); Singkep (Indonesia); Soviet Union; Tripoli (Libya); Washington (D.C.); Albums (Books); Daguerreotypes (photographs); Glass negatives; Lantern slides; Photoprints; Postcards; Astronomers; Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1880-1968; Bingham, Walter Van Dyke, 1880-1952; Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886; Dickinson, Lavinia Norcross, 1833-1899; Dickinson, Susan Huntington, 1830-1913; Dickinson, Austin, 1829-1895; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911; Loomis, Eben Jenks, 1828-1912; Loomis, Mahlon, 1826-1886; Loomis, Mary Alden Wilder, 1831-1910; Newcomb, Simon, 1835-1909; Shoemaker, William Lukens, 1822-; Stearns, Alfred E. (Alfred Ernest), 1871-1949; Todd, David P. (David Peck), 1855-1939; Todd, Mabel Loomis, 1856-1932; Todd, Sereno Edwards, 1820-1898; Wilder, John Augustus, 1834-1870; Bingham family; Loomis family; Todd family; Wilder family; Amherst College; Vassar College
- PHOTOGRAPHS, Circa 1850s-1966; Series I; 16 linear feet (37 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photographs and negatives from the David Peck Todd, Mabel Loomis Todd, Millicent Todd Bingham, and Loomis-Wilder Family Papers. The series is arranged in the following sections:
  Loomis-Wilder Family
  Peck-Todd Family
  David Peck-Todd
  Mabel Loomis Todd
  Todd Family
  Millicent Todd Bingham
  Walter Van Dyke Bingham
  People
  Places
  Astronomy and astronomers
  Miscellanea
  Those four sections for individuals: David Peck Todd, Mabel Loomis Todd, Millicent Todd Bingham, and Walter Van Dyke Bingham contain a chronological arrangement of portraits for the respective individuals. Additional photographs arranged after these portrait files consist of group photos, photographs of friends, topical files as maintained by the individual, and miscellaneous items.
  The remaining sections in this series are alphabetically arranged by the individual pictured in the photograph or by the location of the photograph.
  Similar photographs are also arranged in the scrapbooks and albums in SERIES II, in the small folios in SERIES IV, and in the large folios in SERIES V. SERIES VI also contains a select number of prints made from both the glass negatives and the lantern slides.
  - Loomis-Wilder Family
    - Loomis, Carrie E., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Loomis, Collette, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Loomis, Mary, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Loomis, Eben Jenks
      - Portraits, [ca1853; ca1913] (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
      - Bermuda trip, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Paintings and sketches, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Loomis, George and Wife, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Loomis, Joseph and Harriet, [ca1915] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Loomis, Mahlon and Achsia, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Loomis, Mary Alden Wilder
      - Portraits, 1853-1910 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
      - With others, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Loomis, Nathan and Waite Barber, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Loomis family—residences
      - Washington, D.C., 1880-1900 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
      - Wellesley, Massachusetts, 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Wilder, Charles and wife, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Wilder, Esther, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Wilder, Herbert and family, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Wilder, John Augustus and Stevens, Sue, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Wilder, Mary Wales Fobes Jones, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Wilder family
      - Coat of arms, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Group portrait—women, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Peck-Todd Family
    - Compton, Charles and Naomi, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Crocker, Mrs. Warren, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Fletcher, Mary Todd, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Gaily, M., undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Ingersoll, Calvin and wife, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Jocelyn(?), Susan, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Peck, David and Sarah, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Peck, Edwin and Sarah, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Rupert, Mrs., undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Smith, Isaac and Leona, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Sunderland, Mary Smith, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Todd, Adelbert; Todd, Hattle, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Todd, J.W. (one photo) (Box 3)
    - Todd, J. E., undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Todd, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Todd, Jay and Amy Peck, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Todd, Josiah, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Todd, Rhoda Peck, n.d (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Todd, Serano Edward, Sr., undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Todd, Serano Edward, Jr. and family, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Todd, Sidney and wife, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Upson, Kate, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Ward, Miss (?)., undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - David Peck Todd
    - Portraits
      - 1864-1886 (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
      - 1890s-1905 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - 1907-1922 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - 1923-1938 (Box 4, Folder 52-54)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Airplane and balloon flights, [ca1909-1925] (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - With Mabel Loomis Todd, 1878; 1909 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Mabel Loomis Todd
    - Portraits
      - 1860s-1899 (Box 4, Folder 57-59)
      - 1890s-1907 (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - 1900-1911 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - 1913-1919 (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - 1920s (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - 1930-1932 October (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous
      - With Millicent Todd Bingham, [ca1880s.] (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - Childhood Friends, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
      - Memorials, undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - St. Louis, Missouri (Louisiana Purchase Exposition & Yosemite Park, 1904-1905 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Todd Family
    - Cruise with D.W. James, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Family composites, undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Groups, Family and friends
      - General, [ca1910s]. (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - Hog Island, Maine, [ca191Os] (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - Maine, Vermont, and New Hampshire, [ca1930s] (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Residences
      - Amherst, Massachusetts
        - Lessey house, 1883-1884 (Box 7, Folder 74)
        - Lincoln house, 1886 (Box 7, Folder 75)
        - "The Dell,", 1887-1898 (Box 7, Folder 76)
        - "Observatory house,", [ca1905] (Box 7, Folder 77-79)
      - Fairhaven, Massachusetts, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Coconut Grove, Florida
        - "El Nido,", undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
        - Matsuba, undated (Box 7, Folder 82-84)
  - Millicent Todd Binghamn
    - Portraits and groups
      - 1882-1888 (Box 8, Folder 85)
      - 1890 (Box 8, Folder 86)
      - 1893-1894 (Box 8, Folder 87)
      - 1895-1897 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      - [ca1898] (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - 1899-1900 (Box 8, Folder 90)
      - 1901(?) (Box 8, Folder 91)
      - 1902-1908 (Box 8, Folder 92-95)
      - 1909 (Box 9, Folder 96)
      - 1911-1912 (Box 9, Folder 97)
      - 1912-1917 (Box 9, Folder 98-99)
      - 1918, France (Box 9, Folder 100)
      - 1920, Wedding to Walter Van Dyke Bingham (Box 9, Folder 101)
      - 1920s, Coconut Grove, Florida (Box 9, Folder 102)
      - 1920s, Maine and Vermont (Box 9, Folder 103)
      - 1921-1926 (Box 9, Folder 104-108)
      - 1927 (Box 10, Folder 109)
      - 1928, Florida (Box 10, Folder 110)
      - 1928, Maine (Box 10, Folder 111)
      - 1929-1930 (Box 10, Folder 112)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 113-114)
      - 1934-1944 (Box 11, Folder 115-123)
      - 1946-1950 (Box 12, Folder 124-127)
      - 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 128-130)
      - 1957-1966, undated (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Friends
      - [ca1880, n.d,] (Box 12, Folder 132)
      - 1880-1895 (Box 12, Folder 133-134)
      - 1898, Miss Hersey's School (Box 13, Folder 135)
      - 1899-1900 (Box 13, Folder 136)
      - 1902-1905 (Box 13, Folder 137-138)
    - Topical files
      - Ancestor's Brocades, undated (Box 13, Folder 139)
      - Congrés International de Geographic, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 140)
      - Europe, [ca1910-1951] (Box 13, Folder 141-144)
      - Inventories, 1905-1906; 1968 (Box 13, Folder 145)
      - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, undated (Box 13, Folder 146)
      - Peru, A Land of Contrasts, [ca1914] (Box 13, Folder 147)
      - Plates—Walter V. D. Bingham and Eben Jenks Loomis, undated (Box 14, Folder 148)
      - United States—Florida, undated (Box 14, Folder 149)
      - Vassar College, 1902; 1939; 1961 (Box 14, Folder 150)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 151)
  - Walter Van Dyke Bingham
    - Portraits and groups
      - 1907-1918 (Box 14, Folder 152)
      - 1920-1929 (Box 14, Folder 153)
      - 1930-1952, undated (Box 14, Folder 154-155)
    - Bingham family, [ca1920s-1950s] (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Bingham family—residences, undated (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - People
    - A, undated (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Avery family
      - Benjamin F, undated (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - George Capwell, undated (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - Samuel Look (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - Susannah Howes Look (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - William Sidney (Box 15, Folder 159)
      - Family (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - B, undated (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Cable, George Washington—Clark, John Bates, undated (Box 15, Folder 161)
    - Clarke, James F. and Esther, undated (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Clemmer, Mary—Cooley, Mary Elizabeth, undated (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - Coonley family—Cutler family, undated (Box 16, Folder 164)
    - Corwine, Dessie, undated (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - D, undated (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - Davis, Elmer and family, undated (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - Dickinson, Emily, undated (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Dickinson, Lavinia Norcross, undated (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - Dickinson, Susan Gilbert, undated (Box 16, Folder 170)
    - Dickinson, William Austin, undated (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - Dickinson family, Amherst, Massachusetts, undated
      - Bullard, Asa (Reverend) and Lucretia (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Currier, Elizabeth Dickinson and Katherine Dickinson Sweetser (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Dickinson, Gilbert (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Dickinson, M. E. (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Dickinson, William (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Dickinson ancestors (?) (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Newman, Mark Haskell and Mary Dickinson (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Sweetser, Katherine Dickinson (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Residences (Box 16, Folder 172)
    - Dickinson family, other locations(?), undated (Box 16, Folder 173)
    - E, undated (Box 16, Folder 174)
    - Emerson, Mrs. with David Peck Todd, undated (Box 17, Folder 175)
    - F, undated (Box 17, Folder 176)
    - G, undated (Box 17, Folder 177)
    - Haechel, Ernst—Higginson, Thomas Wentworth,(Colonel), undated (Box 17, Folder 178)
    - Hilder, Howard—Hitchcock, Bradford, undated (Box 17, Folder 179)
    - Hoar, Mrs.—Houghton Family, undated (Box 17, Folder 180)
    - Howe, Julia Ward—Howe, S. H., undated (Box 17, Folder 181)
    - Hubbard, Elbert—Huntington, T.D., undated (Box 17, Folder 182)
    - I-J, undated (Box 18, Folder 183)
    - James, A. C. and family, undated (Box 18, Folder 184)
    - James, D.W., undated (Box 18, Folder 185)
    - K, undated (Box 18, Folder 186)
    - L-Li, undated (Box 18, Folder 187)
    - Lm-Lz, undated (Box 18, Folder 188)
    - M-Matz, undated (Box 18, Folder 189)
    - Meeks-Milinowski, Marta, undated (Box 18, Folder 190)
      General note
      See also: box 39
    - Mill-Mz, undated (Box 19, Folder 191)
    - N, undated (Box 19, Folder 192)
    - Newcomb, Simon and family, undated (Box 19, Folder 193)
      See also: box 38
    - Noble family, undated (Box 19, Folder 194)
      See also: Steams family
    - O, undated (Box 19, Folder 195)
    - P, undated (Box 19, Folder 196)
    - Palmer, George Freeman, undated (Box 19, Folder 197)
    - Palmer, George H., undated (Box 19, Folder 198-199)
    - Pavlov, V. Ivan, undated (Box 19, Folder 200)
    - R, undated (Box 19, Folder 201)
    - S—Shoemaker, W. L. (Box 20, Folder 202)
    - Sawyer, Elizabeth C. and Middlebrook family, undated (Box 20, Folder 203)
    - Skinners—Snell, undated (Box 20, Folder 204)
    - Spraivka—Symington, undated (Box 20, Folder 205)
    - Stearns family, undated (Box 20, Folder 206)
    - Stearns, Alfred, undated (Box 20, Folder 207)
    - Stearns, Mary E., undated (Box 20, Folder 208)
    - Sweetser family, undated (Box 20, Folder 209)
    - Tenny—Thompson, D. (Box 20, Folder 210)
    - Thompson, "Eddie" A., undated (Box 21, Folder 211)
    - Thompson, R.—Thompson, W., undated (Box 21, Folder 212)
    - Thoreau, Henry David—Turner, H.H., undated (Box 21, Folder 213)
    - U-V, undated (Box 21, Folder 214)
    - W, undated (Box 21, Folder 215)
    - Y, undated (Box 21, Folder 216)
    - Unidentified (2 folders), undated (Box 21, Folder 217-218)
  - Places
    - Africa
      - General (Box 22, Folder 219)
      - Capetown (Box 22, Folder 220)
      - St. Helena (Box 22, Folder 221)
      - Tripoli; Tunis (Box 22, Folder 222)
    - Australia
      - Aborigines—Kerry and Company, Sydney; professional photos with numbered index (Box 22, Folder 223)
    - Bermuda
      - General, 1892-1905 (Box 22, Folder 224)
      - General, 1905 (Box 22, Folder 225)
      - Stereopticon views, 1905 (Box 22, Folder 226)
    - Canada: Rocky: mountains—Cascade Mountain, Mount Donald (Box 22, Folder 227)
    - China
      - General (Box 22, Folder 228)
      - Peking, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 229)
    - Cuba
      - General (Box 23, Folder 230)
      - U.S.—Florida (Box 23, Folder 231)
    - Czechoslovakia (Box 23, Folder 232)
    - Egypt (Box 23, Folder 233)
    - France
      - Grenoble
        - General, 1918 (Box 23, Folder 234)
        - Institute de geographie Alpine, 1918-1919 (Box 23, Folder 235)
      - Rennes—Dreyfus' prison, 1905-1906 (Box 23, Folder 236)
      - World War I
        - Commercial photographs (Box 23, Folder 237)
        - Angers, base hospital
          - photos (Box 23, Folder 238)
          - sketches (Box 23, Folder 239)
      - Views, 1919; 1918 (Box 23, Folder 240)
    - Germany, [ca1906] (Box 23, Folder 241)
    - Great Britain (Box 23, Folder 242)
    - Holland (Box 23, Folder 243)
    - India (Box 23, Folder 244)
    - Ireland (Box 23, Folder 245)
    - Italy (Box 23, Folder 246)
    - Japan
      - Ainu
        - Ainu, 1896 (Box 24, Folder 247-249)
        - Views, 1896 (Box 24, Folder 250-251)
        - Mt. Fuji, 1887 (Box 24, Folder 252-253)
        - Mt. Fuji, 1887 (Box 25, Folder 254)
        - Todd Family, 1887 (Box 25, Folder 255)
      - Esashi
        - Expedition, 1896 (Box 25, Folder 256-257)
    - Palestine
      - Stereopticon views (Box 26, Folder 258)
    - Panama (Box 26, Folder 259)
    - Peru: Expedition and miscellaneous, 1907; 1922 (Box 26, Folder 260)
    - Russia: Expedition and miscellaneous, [illegible] (Box 26, Folder 261-262)
    - Siam: Views, [ca1901?] (Box 26, Folder 263)
    - Singapore, 1956, undated (Box 26, Folder 264)
    - Spain: Granada, undated (Box 26, Folder 265)
    - Switzerland: Stereopticon views (Box 26, Folder 266)
    - Tunisia: Tunis (Box 26, Folder 267)
    - Turkey, [ca1920s] (Box 26, Folder 268)
    - United States
      - Arizona (Box 27, Folder 269)
      - California
        - Views (Box 27, Folder 270)
        - Yosemite Park (Box 27, Folder 271)
      - Colorado
        - Views (Box 27, Folder 272)
        - Pike's Peak, 1893 (Box 27, Folder 273-274)
      - District of Columbia
        See: box 34, folder 347
      - Florida
        - Coconut Grove
          - Views of maps (Box 27, Folder 275)
          - Houses and yachts (Box 27, Folder 276)
          - Views (Box 27, Folder 277)
      - Hawaii (Box 27, Folder 278)
      - Illinois
        - Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 28, Folder 279)
        - Lake Shore Drive, 1903 (Box 28, Folder 280)
      - Maine: Harpswell—Stereopticon views, 1875; 1877 (Box 28, Folder 281)
      - Hog Island, [ca1924-1940, undated]
        - General views (Box 28, Folder 284)
        - "Mavooshen,", [ca1919-1921] (Box 28, Folder 285-286)
        - Memorabilia, 1891 (Box 28)
        - Miscellanea (Box 29, Folder 288)
        - Todd Wildlife Sanctuary—Audobon Nature Camp, [1936-1960, undated] (Box 29, Folder 289-291)
      - Views (Box 29, Folder 292-293)
    - Massachusetts
      - Amherst
        - Civil war soldiers-Frazar Stearns(?) (Box 30, Folder 294)
        - "The Convent"
          - Students, [ca1890-1895] (Box 30, Folder 295)
          - Class photos, [ca1890s-1898] (Box 30, Folder 296)
          - Reunions, 1911, 1915; 1927 (Box 30, Folder 297-298)
          - Teachers (Box 30, Folder 299)
          - Exteriors; Interiors (Box 30, Folder 300)
        - Historical Society (Box 30, Folder 301)
        - Maps (Box 30, Folder 302)
        - Special events—parades, parties (Box 30, Folder 303)
        - Stereopticon views (Box 30, Folder 304-305)
        - Street scenes (Box 30, Folder 306)
        - Views—nature (Box 31, Folder 307)
        - Views—panoramic (Box 31, Folder 308)
      - Amherst College (Box 32, Folder 327)
      - Buildings (Box 32, Folder 310-313)
      - Fraternity Houses (Box 32, Folder 314)
      - Commencements, 1898-1905 (Box 32, Folder 315)
      - Faculty (Box 32, Folder 316)
      - Individuals (Box 32, Folder 317)
      - Students (Box 32, Folder 318)
      - Cambridge, ca1920 (Box 32, Folder 319)
      - Concord (Box 32, Folder 320)
      - Holyoke (Box 32, Folder 321-322)
      - Sunderland
        - Stereopticon views (Box 32, Folder 323-324)
      - Views—unidentified (Box 32, Folder 325)
      - Historic sites and miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 326)
    - Missouri—Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1904 (Box 32, Folder 327)
    - Montana
      - Gallatin (Range) Mountains (Box 32, Folder 328)
      - Boulder Creek, 1891 (Box 33, Folder 329)
    - New Hampshire
      - General (Box 33, Folder 330)
      - Stereopticon views (Box 33, Folder 331)
      - Mettalak Lodge—views (Box 33, Folder 332)
      - Wilder houses (Box 33, Folder 333)
      - Lancaster (Box 33, Folder 334)
    - New Mexico
      - Sante Fé (Box 34, Folder 335)
    - New York
      - Stereopticon views—waterfalls Poughkeepsie (Box 34, Folder 336)
      - Ellis Island (Box 34, Folder 337)
      - Grant's Tomb (Box 34, Folder 338)
      - Pershing's Park, "Taking Down the E1" (Box 34, Folder 339)
      - Otsego (Box 34, Folder 340)
      - Watkins Glen (Box 34, Folder 341)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 34)
    - Rhode Island (Box 34, Folder 342)
    - South Dakota (Box 34, Folder 343)
    - Vermont (Box 34, Folder 344)
    - Virginia (Box 34, Folder 345)
    - Washington (Box 34, Folder 346)
    - Washington, D.C.
      - Fuller House (Box 34, Folder 347)
      - "Henderson Castle" (Box 34, Folder 347)
      - Public buildings (Box 34, Folder 347)
      - Rosedale and Church Park (Box 34, Folder 347)
      - Stereopticon views (Box 34, Folder 348)
    - "The West"
      - Stereopticon views (Box 34, Folder 349)
    - Unidentified
      - Stereopticon views (Box 34, Folder 350)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 351)
  - Astronomy and astronomers
    - General (Box 35, Folder 352)
    - Equipment (Box 35, Folder 353)
    - Individuals (Box 35, Folder 354-355)
    - Observations
      - Coronas (Box 35, Folder 356)
      - Eclipses (Box 35, Folder 357)